<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: tech | Arnab's Universe]]></title>
  <link href="http://arnab.github.com/posts/categories/tech/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://arnab.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-21T21:12:05+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://arnab.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Arnab Deka]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[State of e-commerce in India]]></title>
    <link href="http://arnab.github.com/posts/2012/09/state-of-e-commerce-in-india/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-23T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://arnab.github.com/posts/2012/09/state-of-e-commerce-in-india</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So, since moving back to India 4 months ago, we’ve trying to buy stuff
off the internet, like we did back in Seattle (oh Amazon), from
diapers to audio CDs (whaaaat? I know). While the world is much much
better compared to 2006, there are still some Idiocracies in the UX
and process. There are the big players (<a href="http://www.flipkart.com/">FlipKart</a>, <a href="http://www.infibeam.com/">infibeam</a>
and the like) where (from the 4 months experience) you’d find what you
are looking almost 6-7 times out of 10. The long-tail of e-commerce in
India is the real deal though – the tail is really really long. I use
<a href="http://www.junglee.com/">Junglee.com</a> to find the long time and almost always (9+ out of
10) the things I am looking for are found somewhere. Funny thing is
that you’ll never find two things you need in one site. Over these 4
months, I don’t think any of these sites have come up more than once
in my search.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>To highlight some of the other differences:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>No guest checkout</strong>: Almost nobody has guest checkout. Everybody
  requires you to register and require your email and phone. Most
  the package tracking is done thru SMS so that’s ok, but I’ve had
  some spam (email and SMS) originating from here as well. But for
  the most part, they are well behaved (I don't know why they need
  my birthday or gender to ship stuff me though– anyway they get
  wrong info for such questions ;))</li>
<li><strong>Weak integration with backend</strong>: More than once I have placed
  orders (after signing up etc.) only to be informed later that
  the item is not in stock. The websites are more like marketing
  websites with a cart/checkout process and it looks like the
  orders are processed completely separately.</li>
<li><strong>Cash-On-Delivery</strong>: Almost everyone takes COD orders. I know
  some people don’t like the idea, but for Indian e-commerce it’s
  a must. Mostly because if you pay when you order on the site and
  then you don’t get the thing or get something else, there’s
  pretty much nothing you can do. Most sites will process a refund
  but you have to call them a few times to get that done. And some
  sites only give you a coupon that you can use in their site. So
  COD is heaven-sent and must-needed for such small sites.
  <a href="http://www.flipkart.com/s/help/payments">FlipKart has started doing Card-On-Delivery</a>, which is even better!</li>
<li><strong>Faaaaaast and FREE shipping</strong>: Almost every order I have made
  has been delivered within a few days. In one-third of the cases it’s
  within 2 days. And it’s 99% of the time free shipping.</li>
</ul>


<p>To summarize, for the most part, it’s all good. You can find 9/10
things online and of that you can get 9/10 items delivered at your
doorstep within a reasonable amount of time and pay after you
get/inspect it. But that’s not why I started writing this piece today…</p>

<h2>A uniquely horrible experience at ezmaal.com</h2>

<p>What I wanted to do today was share a very bad experience on one of
these small player’s sites today. Remember the band called
<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Route-Indian-Music-Hindi-Modern/dp/B0013LKL36/">Silk Route</a>? Heard them on radio and remembered how awesome their
music was. Unfortunately the album’s not on spotify or in Amazon/MP3.
So I looked up FlipKart (out of stock) and Junglee. That’s where I
found <a href="http://www.ezmaal.com/">ezmaal.com</a> – and they had it in stock! So I went through
the registration process and signed up for an account.</p>

<p>Now, I use the <a href="https://agilebits.com/onepassword">most excellent 1Password</a> for creating random
passwords for every site and to manage signing-in/out. Did the same on
ezmaal too – and it was all fine and dandy and got an account created.
Now, just before checking out I wanted to see if the login/logout was
working (you never know with small sites). So I opened up the site in
an <a href="http://support.google.com/chrome/bin/answer.py?hl=en&amp;answer=95464">incognito window</a> and tried loggin in. Here’s the screenshot of
what I got back: [![ezmaal login failure][11]][11]
click to see larger image</p>

<ol>
<li>They throw a really garbage un-customized ASP.net error in the
customer’s face. It means nothing to me!</li>
<li>They are trying to validate my password for script-injection. I
don’t think they are actively doing this, but it’s probably part of
ASP.net and they have not tested and not coded to handle login
failures. Really really bad if the login on your site throws up gibberish.</li>
<li><strong>Password displayed on screen</strong>: The worst part is that they
print my password three times on the screen, verbatim. Thank God I use
1Password and have a random (and more importantly, different) password
on every site. But like most customer’s if I had a
one-password-for-all and used that in here, it’s as good as being
leaked. If nowhere else, this will be on their server-logs. An
employee only need to grep for <code>Password\=</code> in the logs. On top of
this, with this kind of an experience, I have no faith that they
salt/hash the passwords. I am more willing to believe that they keep
it all in cleartext in a SQLServer database.</li>
</ol>


<p>I have seen bad e-commerce sites before, but will I shop at a place
which does not care about my online security? No way in hell (yeah, I
did not complete that order)!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quick howto on accessing Rails Properties]]></title>
    <link href="http://arnab.github.com/posts/2011/04/quick-howto-accessing-rails-properties/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-08T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://arnab.github.com/posts/2011/04/quick-howto-accessing-rails-properties</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When you create a new Rails app the default static page (public/index.html) page shows a lot of details about the app. Here’s a quick how-to show these details (the idea is to probably show these on a /ping route (or a debug parameter on any page maybe) – so you can quickly monitor your app – it’s state, active_record state etc.).</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><strong>Rails 3</strong>: browse the <a href="https://github.com/rails/rails/blob/v3.0.6/railties/lib/rails/info.rb">source-code at railties/lib/rails/info.rb</a></p>

<p>Or see:
<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/911091.js?file=rails_306_properties.rb'></script>
<noscript><pre><code># see https://github.com/rails/rails/blob/v3.0.6/railties/lib/rails/info.rb

@properties = {
  :ruby =&gt; &quot;#{RUBY_VERSION} (#{RUBY_PLATFORM})&quot;,
  :rubygem =&gt; Gem::RubyGemsVersion,
  :rack =&gt; ::Rack.release,
  :rails =&gt; Rails::VERSION::STRING,
  :app_root =&gt; File.expand_path(Rails.root),
  :env =&gt; Rails.env,
  :db_adapter =&gt; ActiveRecord::Base.configurations[Rails.env]['adapter'],
  :db_schema_version =&gt; (ActiveRecord::Migrator.current_version || nil),
  :middleware =&gt; Rails.configuration.middleware.map(&amp;:inspect),
}
</code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>

<p><strong>Rails 2</strong>: browse the <a href="https://github.com/rails/rails/blob/v2.0.2/railties/builtin/rails_info/rails/info.rb">source-code at railties/builtin/rails_info/rails/info.rb</a></p>

<p>Or see:
<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/911091.js?file=rails_202_properties.rb'></script>
<noscript><pre><code># see https://github.com/rails/rails/blob/v2.0.2/railties/builtin/rails_info/rails/info.rb

@properties = {
  :ruby =&gt; &quot;#{RUBY_VERSION} (#{RUBY_PLATFORM})&quot;,
  :rubygem =&gt; Gem::RubyGemsVersion,
  :rails =&gt; Rails::VERSION::STRING,
  :app_root =&gt; File.expand_path(RAILS_ROOT),
  :env =&gt; RAILS_ENV,
  :db_adapter =&gt; ActiveRecord::Base.configurations[RAILS_ENV]['adapter'],
  :db_schema_version =&gt; (ActiveRecord::Migrator.current_version || nil),
}
</code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>

<p>Till the next time…</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interesting Job Advertisement]]></title>
    <link href="http://arnab.github.com/posts/2009/09/interesting-job-advertisement/"/>
    <updated>2009-09-22T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://arnab.github.com/posts/2009/09/interesting-job-advertisement</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A recent job opening advert (from <a href="http://vark.com/jobs#feeng">Aardvark, for a Front-End Web Developers</a>) goes:</p>

<blockquote><p>Required Skills:
* Fluency in HTML and CSS
* Experience taking mockups and turning them into standards-compliant HTML/CSS
* Expertise in achieving cross-browser compatibility in IE, Firefox, and Safari
* Experience in implementing grid-based layouts in HTML/CSS
* Experience in an agile development environment</p>

<p>Pluses:
* Interest in user experience design and graphic design
* Experience in Javascript and Ruby on Rails
* History of side projects and interest in social media, browsers, and mobile web
* Obsession with new technologies and open source tools
* Experimental, user focused, and iterative
* Previous startup experience</p></blockquote>

<p>I felt the Pluses section was very interesting, specially (you kinda see the others on Rails related job boards anyway):
* History of side projects and interest in social media, browsers, and mobile web
* Obsession with new technologies and open source tools</p>

<p>Shows how today’s start-ups value people who are really interested in what they do (and not just in for the money). An encouraging view of the world indeed – now I just have to get on it and get those much needed Plusses into my skills bag <img src="http://www.arnab-deka.com/posts/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" /></p>

<p>Note to my employers, friends, well wishers and anyone else interested: This does not mean I am looking for a job! I love the job I have right now and am just happy to see the importance of “passion” in the world’s view of an ideal employee increasing!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rails Guides on my Kindle DX!!! (or any webpage for that matter)
]]></title>
    <link href="http://arnab.github.com/posts/2009/09/rails-guides-on-my-kindle-dx-or-any-webpage-for-that-matter/"/>
    <updated>2009-09-18T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://arnab.github.com/posts/2009/09/rails-guides-on-my-kindle-dx-or-any-webpage-for-that-matter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I got a <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0015TCML0?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=arnsblo-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B0015TCML0">Amazon Kindle DX</a><img src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=arnsblo-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=B0015TCML0" alt="" /> for a birthday gift! Thanks Ujwala!</p>

<p>And so far I am loving it. It’s better to read on compared to Kindle 1 (which, BTW, Ujwala had gifted to me last year) – and the native PDF support (and the search-anywhere) is awesome! The experimental browser that comes with the DX is much much improved compared to Kindle 1st Gen.</p>

<p>So I was reading more about <a href="http://guides.rubyonrails.org/routing.html">Rails Routing in the rails-guides</a>. And while I was in the bus today morning I wanted to read that on the Kindle (coz it is a pleasure to read on it). So I fired up the guides page on the experimental browser – it works, but reading a PDF or a Kindle-formatted book is so much better.</p>

<p>So I got this simple idea. Print the web page as a PDF and e-mail it to your Kindle. Here’s what I did:</p>

<ol>
<li>Go to the site</li>
<li>Print – (PDF format “saved to file” instead of sending it to a printer). I was on Linux – Mac also has the “Print to PDF/PS support by default, for Windows you’ll need to get <a href="http://www.cutepdf.com/">CutePDF</a> installed)</li>
<li>e-mail it to your Kindle address (I also uploaded it to my dropbox – so I can get it later on) and you are done!</li>
</ol>


<p>(BTW, dropbox is an amazing thing – if you use multiple computers/OS, you have to try this thing. If you are going to try it out (for free), help me out – <a href="https://www.getdropbox.com/referrals/NTEzMDYwMzk">use my Dropbox referral link</a>)</p>

<p>So there you go – another easy way to get web-content for free on your Kindle. Go on enjoy the book now.</p>

<p><strong>Blog-Notes</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0015TCML0?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=arnsblo-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B0015TCML0">Amazon Kindle DX</a></li>
<li><a href="http://guides.rubyonrails.org">Rails Guides – excellent info on the RubyOnRails framework</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.cutepdf.com/">CutePDF</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.getdropbox.com/">DropBox</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNU Screen]]></title>
    <link href="http://arnab.github.com/posts/2009/07/gnu-screen/"/>
    <updated>2009-07-20T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://arnab.github.com/posts/2009/07/gnu-screen</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you have nothing to do with Linux you probably can stop reading now. Unless you want to get introduced to a very nice tool in the Linux world. I can say without doubt that this saves me at least an hour every month. In addition it gets you away from doing some mundane “set-up” like things every time to start working. It has a load of features but today I’ll just scratch the surface. But it’ll be enough to start you off and I promise you’ll be glad you found screen.</p>

<p>One of the programs that I love and can’t go through the day without is <a href="http://www.gnu.org/software/screen/">GNU Screen</a>. It’s like a Window manager, but only for your terminals. You know, like you are working with so many terminals/consoles/terminal-windows all the time (one to the DB, one with vim open, one to run the tests, one to run the program etc., one to watch the logs, a few to prod boxes etc.). And then you disconnect and then reconnect (from home, somewhere else) and you have to set-up all that again?</p>

<p>Yeah screen can help you with all that. My work pattern involves connecting to a screen session (and I get all the windows/context loaded). Whether I connect from work, home from somewhere else, all I have to say is:</p>

<pre><code>$ screen -ls (to see what sessions I have running)
$ screen -R some-session-name
</code></pre>

<p>And it’s wicked-easy to switch between different windows, search through your history etc. You can also configure it to do a few “start-up” things every time. For example, at home, I have screen</p>

<ol>
<li>configured to Open 4 windows when it starts up and</li>
<li>have window-0 go to my code dir (to teh root of my <a href="http://rubyonrails.org/">RubyOnRails</a> part of the site)</li>
<li>start up <a href="http://nubyonrails.com/articles/autotest-rails">auto-test</a> on window-1</li>
<li>show the logs on window-2</li>
<li>ssh into the <a href="http://www.bluehost.com/">blue host</a> (which hosts my site)</li>
</ol>


<p>Since the windows are persisted, I don’t have to do all these things every time I connect (for a lazy programmer (and all programmers are lazy aren’t they?) that’s a lot of help). You can even share the screens with someone else (I have not tried that yet though).</p>

<p>Anyway, I hope you are sold by now. Even if you are not, spend some time (shouldn’t be more than a couple of hours) installing/configuring/running screen and you will soon reap the rewards. To get you started:</p>

<ul>
<li>The GNU Screen home-page: <a href="http://www.gnu.org/software/screen/">http://www.gnu.org/software/screen</a></li>
<li>A good guide to installing/setting-up/using: <a href="http://magazine.redhat.com/2007/09/27/a-guide-to-gnu-screen">http://magazine.redhat.com/2007/09/27/a-guide-to-gnu-screen</a></li>
<li>Once you start liking it you’ll need a cheat-sheet: <a href="http://aperiodic.net/screen/quick_reference?do=show">http://aperiodic.net/screen/quick_reference?do=show</a></li>
</ul>


<p>A word about configuring: heard that Ubuntu will soon shipping with decent .screenrc (sane default configuration) so you don’t have to. Meanwhile you can configure it yourself (as in the Red Hat guide above) or look at these cool options: <a href="http://linux.dsplabs.com.au/gnu-screen-screenrc-configuration-file-p13/">http://linux.dsplabs.com.au/gnu-screen-screenrc-configuration-file-p13/</a>. Here is my .screenrc:</p>

<pre><code>vbell off
vbell_msg "Ring"

# detach on hangup
autodetach on

# don&amp;#039;t display copyright page
startup_message off

# scroll back
defscrollback 1000

# setup the caption
hardstatus alwayslastline "%{-b gk}%-w%{+b kg}%50&gt;%n %t%{-b gk}%+w %=%C%&lt; "

# right/left bindings
bindkey "^[[c" next
bindkey "^[[d" prev
bindkey "^[[b" focus

# Set the altscreen so that when you quit vi, it will go back to
# what it was before
altscreen on
</code></pre>

<p>And finally, my delicious links for screen. </p>
Happy “screen”-ing <img src="http://www.arnab-deka.com/posts/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
