<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: on life | Arnab's Universe]]></title>
  <link href="http://arnab-deka.com/posts/categories/on-life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://arnab-deka.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-07T22:42:34+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://arnab-deka.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Arnab Deka]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[State of e-commerce in India]]></title>
    <link href="http://arnab-deka.com/posts/2012/09/state-of-e-commerce-in-india/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-23T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://arnab-deka.com/posts/2012/09/state-of-e-commerce-in-india</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So, since moving back to India 4 months ago, we’ve trying to buy stuff
off the internet, like we did back in Seattle (oh Amazon), from
diapers to audio CDs (whaaaat? I know). While the world is much much
better compared to 2006, there are still some Idiocracies in the UX
and process. There are the big players (<a href="http://www.flipkart.com/">FlipKart</a>, <a href="http://www.infibeam.com/">infibeam</a>
and the like) where (from the 4 months experience) you’d find what you
are looking almost 6-7 times out of 10. The long-tail of e-commerce in
India is the real deal though – the tail is really really long. I use
<a href="http://www.junglee.com/">Junglee.com</a> to find the long time and almost always (9+ out of
10) the things I am looking for are found somewhere. Funny thing is
that you’ll never find two things you need in one site. Over these 4
months, I don’t think any of these sites have come up more than once
in my search.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>To highlight some of the other differences:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>No guest checkout</strong>: Almost nobody has guest checkout. Everybody
  requires you to register and require your email and phone. Most
  the package tracking is done thru SMS so that’s ok, but I’ve had
  some spam (email and SMS) originating from here as well. But for
  the most part, they are well behaved (I don&rsquo;t know why they need
  my birthday or gender to ship stuff me though– anyway they get
  wrong info for such questions ;))</li>
<li><strong>Weak integration with backend</strong>: More than once I have placed
  orders (after signing up etc.) only to be informed later that
  the item is not in stock. The websites are more like marketing
  websites with a cart/checkout process and it looks like the
  orders are processed completely separately.</li>
<li><strong>Cash-On-Delivery</strong>: Almost everyone takes COD orders. I know
  some people don’t like the idea, but for Indian e-commerce it’s
  a must. Mostly because if you pay when you order on the site and
  then you don’t get the thing or get something else, there’s
  pretty much nothing you can do. Most sites will process a refund
  but you have to call them a few times to get that done. And some
  sites only give you a coupon that you can use in their site. So
  COD is heaven-sent and must-needed for such small sites.
  <a href="http://www.flipkart.com/s/help/payments">FlipKart has started doing Card-On-Delivery</a>, which is even better!</li>
<li><strong>Faaaaaast and FREE shipping</strong>: Almost every order I have made
  has been delivered within a few days. In one-third of the cases it’s
  within 2 days. And it’s 99% of the time free shipping.</li>
</ul>


<p>To summarize, for the most part, it’s all good. You can find 9/10
things online and of that you can get 9/10 items delivered at your
doorstep within a reasonable amount of time and pay after you
get/inspect it. But that’s not why I started writing this piece today…</p>

<h2>A uniquely horrible experience at ezmaal.com</h2>

<p>What I wanted to do today was share a very bad experience on one of
these small player’s sites today. Remember the band called
<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Route-Indian-Music-Hindi-Modern/dp/B0013LKL36/">Silk Route</a>? Heard them on radio and remembered how awesome their
music was. Unfortunately the album’s not on spotify or in Amazon/MP3.
So I looked up FlipKart (out of stock) and Junglee. That’s where I
found <a href="http://www.ezmaal.com/">ezmaal.com</a> – and they had it in stock! So I went through
the registration process and signed up for an account.</p>

<p>Now, I use the <a href="https://agilebits.com/onepassword">most excellent 1Password</a> for creating random
passwords for every site and to manage signing-in/out. Did the same on
ezmaal too – and it was all fine and dandy and got an account created.
Now, just before checking out I wanted to see if the login/logout was
working (you never know with small sites). So I opened up the site in
an <a href="http://support.google.com/chrome/bin/answer.py?hl=en&amp;answer=95464">incognito window</a> and tried loggin in. Here’s the screenshot of
what I got back: [![ezmaal login failure][11]][11]
click to see larger image</p>

<ol>
<li>They throw a really garbage un-customized ASP.net error in the
customer’s face. It means nothing to me!</li>
<li>They are trying to validate my password for script-injection. I
don’t think they are actively doing this, but it’s probably part of
ASP.net and they have not tested and not coded to handle login
failures. Really really bad if the login on your site throws up gibberish.</li>
<li><strong>Password displayed on screen</strong>: The worst part is that they
print my password three times on the screen, verbatim. Thank God I use
1Password and have a random (and more importantly, different) password
on every site. But like most customer’s if I had a
one-password-for-all and used that in here, it’s as good as being
leaked. If nowhere else, this will be on their server-logs. An
employee only need to grep for <code>Password\=</code> in the logs. On top of
this, with this kind of an experience, I have no faith that they
salt/hash the passwords. I am more willing to believe that they keep
it all in cleartext in a SQLServer database.</li>
</ol>


<p>I have seen bad e-commerce sites before, but will I shop at a place
which does not care about my online security? No way in hell (yeah, I
did not complete that order)!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[1Password for Mac. Free. Really.]]></title>
    <link href="http://arnab-deka.com/posts/2010/11/1password-for-mac-free-really/"/>
    <updated>2010-11-26T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://arnab-deka.com/posts/2010/11/1password-for-mac-free-really</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I use and love <a href="http://agilewebsolutions.com/onepassword">1Password</a> on my Mac every day – it has become one of those things I can’t live without, and is easily worth the $40 price.</p>

<p>Yesterday they announced their very generous ThanksGiving offer: <a href="http://agile.ws/ThankYou">Free 1-for-1 license</a>. So I can give away a Free 1Password for Mac license – and since no one else in my family has started using a Mac full-time yet, I will give it away to you!</p>

<p>Just add a comment here – saying why I should give it away to you and wait for a few hours. I will pick one person here and send them the license. Make sure you leave some contact so I can get back to you. How will I pick? The most entertaining comment of course. But yeah – don’t hold me to it, I might just randomly pick someone.</p>

<p>Thank you for playing!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A beautiful foggy autumn morning]]></title>
    <link href="http://arnab-deka.com/posts/2009/10/a-beautiful-foggy-autumn-morning-echo-lake-view-from-my-house-iphonepicb/"/>
    <updated>2009-10-22T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://arnab-deka.com/posts/2009/10/a-beautiful-foggy-autumn-morning-echo-lake-view-from-my-house-iphonepicb</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Echo lake, view from my house. Taken with my iPhone and enhanced with the free Photoshop.com app:</p>

<p><img class="left <a" src="href="http://posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/arnab/FxteHueeFwrqAflpJqfdjFhCGIiqmxehipFhElFobGurIylFdmjChaegDpBm/image.jpg.scaled500.jpg">http://posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/arnab/FxteHueeFwrqAflpJqfdjFhCGIiqmxehipFhElFobGurIylFdmjChaegDpBm/image.jpg.scaled500.jpg</a>" title="Echo Lake" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Photos: Hamilton Viewpoint Park and Alki Beach, West Seattle]]></title>
    <link href="http://arnab-deka.com/posts/2009/08/photos-hamilton-park-and-alki-beach/"/>
    <updated>2009-08-04T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://arnab-deka.com/posts/2009/08/photos-hamilton-park-and-alki-beach</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On a photo uploading spree today.</p>

<p>The first album consists photos from Hamilton Park and Alki Beach, a beautiful area in West Seattle. Because of it’s location, you get great views of Seattle and the Harbor from here, specially great in the evening.</p>

<p>Hamilton Viewpoint Park: See details <a href="http://www.gonorthwest.com/Washington/Seattle/viewpoints/hamilton.htm">here</a> and the <a href="http://www.seattle.gov/parks/park_detail.asp?id=454">Seattle gov parks page</a>.</p>

<p><strong>The full album</strong> (only 26 pics – easy to click through and to add comments too) <strong>is on my smugmug site: <a href="http://arnab-o-scope.smugmug.com/gallery/9163956_kwkf7">http://arnab-o-scope.smugmug.com/gallery/9163956_kwkf7</a></strong>.</p>

<p>Here are a few excerpts:*   [![macbook][4]][4]
*   [![Seattle downtown basking in the evening glory][5]][5]
*   [![Downtown Seattle Closeup][6]][6]
*   [![Pinkish sunset over Mt Rainier][7]][7]
*   [![a couple getting married][8]][8]
*   [![A state ferry with the Space Needle and Cascade mountains in the backdrop][9]][9]
*   [![another shot with the mountains and the needle][10]][10]
*   [![On the way to Death Valley][11]][11]
*   [![On the way to Death Valley][12]][12]
*   [![Badwater Basin][13]][13]
*   [![Bad Water Basin][14]][14]
*   [![Red Rock Canyon][15]][15]
*   [![Vegas Strip][16]][16]
*   [![Fabulous Las Vegas][17]][17]
*   [![Fabulous Las Vegas][18]][18]
*   [![Around US][19]][19]
*   [![Red Rock Canyon][20]][20]
*   [![Red Rock Canyon][21]][21]
*   [![Red Rock Canyon][22]][22]
*   [![ARCL Summer 2008 3rd Place Trophy (Eagles)][23]][23]
*   [![Arnab Deka][24]][24]
*   [![Arnab][25]][25]</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I didn't tip the cab today]]></title>
    <link href="http://arnab-deka.com/posts/2009/02/i-didnt-tip-the-cab-today/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-11T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://arnab-deka.com/posts/2009/02/i-didnt-tip-the-cab-today</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just got back from Las Vegas. The trip was good (details and pics coming soon) – but I did not tip the cab on my way back from <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seattle-Tacoma_International_Airport">Sea-Tac</a> Airport to my place today.</p>

<p>I usually do. And a lot. In fact my friends say that I tip too much – whether in restaurants, in saloons or in cabs. Today was different – and I honestly did not think that the driver deserved even a cent. Moreover, I actually wrote down a big “$ 0.00″ in the tip section of the receipt. Here’s what happened, from scratch.</p>

<p>Got down at <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seattle-Tacoma_International_Airport">Sea-Tac</a> around 9:35 PST. The Seattle Metro bus 194 had just left and the next one was a 30 minute wait. BTW, the Metro 194 route is a real nice transport to/from the airport if you are in downtown Seattle. The route is via I-5 and it takes about 30 min to get there – hassle free. And after you read what I am about to write, I hope you will also rate the Metro 194 as a good service – at least better than some cabs.</p>

<p>So we decided to get a cab home – and got into one. I have taken cabs from SeaTac to my house 7 times in the last 1.5 years. And I am positive that it was always around $34-$36 – and I would mark it up to $40 and a nice “thank you”. Today it ran up to $41.</p>

<p>Anyway that’s not the problem – I wanted to know if the fare had increased (I remember that there is a flat rate of around $33 to/from SeaTac and downtown). So I asked the driver if there was a flat rate from SeaTac. He said that it’s $35 flat from downtown to SeaTac but not while returning. And I thought they have a card in every cab that states the flat rates – so I asked for it. The guy was pissed off. I don’t know what crime I committed (as far as I know, I asked him in the most polite way possible – I didn’t want to come off as a cheapo).</p>

<p>He got agitated and said that there’s no such card, the fares increased in October and I can pay him $41 now. So I asked him if he can swipe my card (I was carrying $40 cash – as my previous experience had thought me to to). He took the card, swiped it and asked me to sign my receipt.</p>

<p>It was all okay till this part – here’s when the fun started. I was giving him my autograph when he started off in Hindi – “Tum saale Desi logon ka yahii problem hai”. (for my non-hindi-speaking friends, that means something like “This is the problem with you Desi (Indian) people”) hmmm… I was not gonna take that sitting back – and I thought it was a racial slur. As far as I am concerned, the situation or my behavior did not warrant a racial slur (really, nothing does. Or should). I had never heard (or maybe I never recognized it) racial abuse so far – and that too from another Indian/Pakistani? <img src="http://www.arnab-deka.com/posts/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":-)" /> . So I told him, in English, as I didn’t want to go down this path – that, this was uncalled-for and was really bad.</p>

<p>By now he was out of control – shouting and enraged (and I swear I did not call him any names at all). So I said, I am not going to sign the receipt if this goes on. I asked him to shake hands, take the receipt and go home (Ok, even I was not the most polite person by now, but I was not bad-mouthing). His reply was – “Pay and get out of my cab.” He tried to threaten me by picking up the phone and starting to dial someone. I thought it was the police – and that they would be fair mediators <img src="http://www.arnab-deka.com/posts/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":-)" /> So I said, “Who are you calling, the Police? Ok – let’s wait for them – I am not signing the receipt till then.” And then he gave in, again shouted me to get out of his car.</p>

<p>Anyway, I got his badge number and details – and he asked me if I was going to file a complaint. On hearing “yes, obviously” he shrugged and muttered something.</p>

<p>So – I just left all the details of the complaint on the <a href="http://www.seattle.gov/consumeraffairs/fsw&amp;m.htm">Seattle TaxiCab complaint hotline</a> (BTW – a nice IVR system. I initially expected them to call me back during “working hours” – the number’s 206-296-TAXI). Also left a voice mail with STITA cabs complaint line.</p>

<p>Maybe the fare has risen and is now more than $40. Maybe the sites that Google turns up are still not updated with the latest fares (they still say the fare should be around $35) &ndash;
<a href="http://www.engr.washington.edu/epp/icders/transp.html">http://www.engr.washington.edu/epp/icders/transp.html</a>
<a href="http://www.portseattle.org/seatac/ground/groundrates.shtml#d">http://www.portseattle.org/seatac/ground/groundrates.shtml#d</a></p>

<p>Or maybe the meter was rigged? Maybe STITA cabs really deserve the <a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/stita-taxi-seattle">bad bad reviews they have on yelp</a> (oh and they are going to get another one in a few minutes).</p>

<p>But what I am sure of is that it did not deserve all the rude behavior, racial slurs I got from the driver.</p>

<p>Let’s see what turns up – both complaint lines acknowledged the entry and said that they will get back (in fact I have heard good things about Seattle Cab complaints) within a few days. Will update the blog when I hear from them.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
