<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: travel | Arnab's Universe]]></title>
  <link href="http://arnab-deka.com/posts/categories/travel/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://arnab-deka.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-07T22:42:34+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://arnab-deka.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Arnab Deka]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the Coastal Classic Train to Seward.]]></title>
    <link href="http://arnab-deka.com/posts/2010/08/on-the-coastal-classic-train-to-seward/"/>
    <updated>2010-08-14T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://arnab-deka.com/posts/2010/08/on-the-coastal-classic-train-to-seward</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/arnab/nrJwodabpHxsDoxudxwGdGICCFpbecttjjjuIcvrsgzjEqzhyzaJbDcBuHJg/file.jpeg.scaled500.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>On the Coastal Classic Train to Seward. Look at the route. #Alaska #vacation via <a href="http://www.osfoora.com">Osfoora</a></p>

<p><a href="http://posterous.com">Posted via email</a> from <a href="http://arnab.posterous.com/on-the-coastal-classic-train-to-seward">arnab’s posterous</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Colorado Pictures (2009 Nov)]]></title>
    <link href="http://arnab-deka.com/posts/2009/12/colorado-pictures-2009-nov/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-20T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://arnab-deka.com/posts/2009/12/colorado-pictures-2009-nov</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Pics from the Colorado trip back in November, 2009 (with Ujwala and Maa). We spent two days in Rocky Mountain National Park and a day over in Colorado Springs and around (Manitou Springs, Pikes Peak – highest peak in that area).</p>

<p>It’s heavenly – have to go there again in Spring 2010 )along with the parks in Wyoming, Montana).</p>

<p>Click on the photo to get to my SmugMug page – feel free to leave a comment <img src="http://www.arnab-deka.com/posts/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" />
[![][3]][3]</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Las Vegas Trip Photos]]></title>
    <link href="http://arnab-deka.com/posts/2009/02/las-vegas-trip-photos/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-13T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://arnab-deka.com/posts/2009/02/las-vegas-trip-photos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>And I have to remember this blog for ever. I wrote it right at 1234567890 UTC (and on Friday the 13th!)
<img src="http://www.arnab-deka.com/posts/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":-)" /></p>

<pre><code>$ watch -n1 -d &amp;#039;date +%s; expr 1234567890 - `date +%s`&amp;#039;
Every 1s: date +%s; expr 1234567890 - `date +%s`

1234567890
0
</code></pre>

<p>Last weekend I, <strong>Ujwala </strong>and two of my old time friends, <strong>Daboo </strong>and <strong>Nandini </strong>met up in <strong>Vegas</strong>.</p>

<p>We went around, saw the fabulous (should I say decadently smashing) hotels/resorts/casinos and did a little money-wasting (it would be hard to call slot machines gambling). The <a href="http://www.cirquedusoleil.com/CirqueDuSoleil/en/showstickets/mystere/mystere-Las-Vegas.htm">Cirque Du Soleil Mystere show</a> was really superb – perhaps the best live performance (in theater/circus area) I have seen. The crazy horse show was… well… disappointing.</p>

<p>We had <a href="http://www.nps.gov/grca/">Grand Canyon</a> in mind when we were planning for the trip but heavy snow and bad weather made us cancel it. And <a href="http://www.usbr.gov/lc/hooverdam/">Hoover Dam</a> too… <img src="http://www.arnab-deka.com/posts/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_sad.gif" alt=":-(" /></p>

<p>But we did go over to <a href="http://www.nps.gov/deva/">Death Valley National Park</a> Area and <a href="http://www.redrockcanyonlv.org/">Red Rock Canyon</a> – was rocking!</p>

<p><strong>My top five</strong> of the trip are &ndash;
1) <a href="http://www.cirquedusoleil.com/CirqueDuSoleil/en/showstickets/mystere/mystere-Las-Vegas.htm">Cirque Du Soleil Mystere show</a>
2) <a href="http://www.redrockcanyonlv.org/">Red Rock Canyon</a>
3) <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Badwater">Badwater Basin</a> (and the drive to/from)
4) <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Las_Vegas_Strip">The fabulous Vegas Strip</a> – special mention goes to <a href="http://www.bellagio.com/amenities/fountains-of-bellagio.aspx">Bellagio fountains</a>, the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wynn_Las_Vegas">Wynn resort</a>, The <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qD5yUQqmSLQ&amp;feature=related">Mirage Volcanic fountains</a>
5) The view from top of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stratosphere_Las_Vegas">Stratosphere tower</a></p>

<p>Taking this opportunity, let me showcase a few of my pictures. All my photos from the trip at <strong><a href="http://arnab-o-scope.smugmug.com/gallery/7346028_QEfwd#472798549_SQvyN">arnab-o-scope on smugmug</a></strong>.</p>

<p>Daboo also took some great pictures. They are at <a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/nandini.gogoi/LasVegas?authkey=rV1O2jVklyo#">Nandini’s picasa album</a>)</p>

<ul>
<li>[![macbook][17]][17]</li>
<li>[![Seattle downtown basking in the evening glory][18]][18]</li>
<li>[![Downtown Seattle Closeup][19]][19]</li>
<li>[![Pinkish sunset over Mt Rainier][20]][20]</li>
<li>[![a couple getting married][21]][21]</li>
<li>[![A state ferry with the Space Needle and Cascade mountains in the backdrop][22]][22]</li>
<li>[![another shot with the mountains and the needle][23]][23]</li>
<li>[![On the way to Death Valley][24]][24]</li>
<li>[![On the way to Death Valley][25]][25]</li>
<li>[![Badwater Basin][26]][26]</li>
<li>[![Bad Water Basin][27]][27]</li>
<li>[![Red Rock Canyon][28]][28]</li>
<li>[![Vegas Strip][29]][29]</li>
<li>[![Fabulous Las Vegas][30]][30]</li>
<li>[![Fabulous Las Vegas][31]][31]</li>
<li>[![Around US][32]][32]</li>
<li>[![Red Rock Canyon][33]][33]</li>
<li>[![Red Rock Canyon][34]][34]</li>
<li>[![Red Rock Canyon][35]][35]</li>
<li>[![ARCL Summer 2008 3rd Place Trophy (Eagles)][36]][36]</li>
<li>[![Arnab Deka][37]][37]</li>
<li>[![Arnab][38]][38]</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Grand Coulee Dam Trip]]></title>
    <link href="http://arnab-deka.com/posts/2008/09/grand-coulee-dam-trip/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-26T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://arnab-deka.com/posts/2008/09/grand-coulee-dam-trip</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Update on 12/24 – finally updated the photos. They have come out really well!
Here’s one of the sunset – <a href="http://tinyurl.com/ArnabPicsSunsetGC">http://tinyurl.com/ArnabPicsSunsetGC</a>. And another one of the highway along the hauntingly beautiful landscape – <a href="http://tinyurl.com/ArnabHighwayGC">http://tinyurl.com/ArnabHighwayGC</a>.</p>

<p>View the full smugmug gallery: <a href="http://tinyurl.com/ArnabAlbumGC">http://tinyurl.com/ArnabAlbumGC</a></p>

<ul>
<li><ul>
<li>*My Maa is here for a month. Reached here this week.</p></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>This weekend we (Maa, Ujwala and me) are off to Grand Coulee Dam – the biggest concrete dam in North America – generates about 6500 Mega Watts – the highest for any dam in the world.</p>

<p>The drive from Seattle is beautiful – it passes through the Seattle hills/lakes, the Snoqualmie area (water falls, snow-capped mountains and passes), beautiful farm-lands and then on to the arid eastern Washinton area. The route follows the Columbia river and there are some really amazing viewpoints over the gorges along the way. There is a sound and laser show on the dam every evening from 8:30 PM (May-September) – the lasers use the dam as the screen! It is supposedly the largest such sound and light show in the world! The Columbia rivers history is depicted – so all that this weekend.</p>

<p>and the trip weather looks good: <a href="http://www.weatherbonk.com/weather/routeWeather.jsp?start=Seattle%2C+washington&amp;end=Grand+Coulee+Dam%2C+WA&amp;speedString=60&amp;departureDayString=1&amp;departureTimeString=9&amp;_booleanHelper_searchRangeDates=searchRangeDates&amp;dayRange=1&amp;hourRange=1&amp;routePath=&amp;_submit=go&amp;_id=&amp;_className=weathermaps.weather.path.RouteRequest">weatherbonk link</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A memorable flight]]></title>
    <link href="http://arnab-deka.com/posts/2008/02/a-memorable-flight/"/>
    <updated>2008-02-23T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://arnab-deka.com/posts/2008/02/a-memorable-flight</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This has got to be the most beautiful sights I have ever seen! No second thoughts whatsoever.</p>

<p>So I miss my friends in NY and not yet full used to my life in Seattle – so to get a taste of how life was, back in NY, I am traveling there this weekend. Right now I am about 30 min away from Seattle – wait, that’s flight time – so it should be around 300 miles (since an Airbus A320 travels around 560-620 mph in good weather conditions and I cannot say there is even a small blemish in the clouds today!
So I must be flying over the Rockies right now – seems like it anyway – Maybe the gorges that I am seeing are parts of the Bryce Canion.</p>

<p>I wish I was a an artist – I wish I could draw this thing – but only if wishes were horses <img src="http://www.arnab-deka.com/posts/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":-)" />
Maybe even the best artist cannot draw this beauty in a physical medium – you have to experience it.</p>

<p>This is my 5th cross-country flight – Coast-to-coast non-stop and I always liked the flights.</p>

<p>At the east coast nothing can beat the majestic show of pomp that NYC skyline is – if you land/take off at night. Oh I don’t know if you’ll get a more engrossing skyline anywhere else in the world – you just have to see the skyscrapers of midtown and downtown rise out (as you descend) of the vast see of light that is the tri-state metropolitan area (NY, NJ and PA).
If you fly to NY from inside the US, you’ll get to see the orange glow of NYC about half an hour before you are anywhere near it. Then you’ll see the sea of light and then in the last moments of your flight you’ll see the Grand NYC skyline emerge from there! It’s like a Hollywood movie – I have to tell you.</p>

<p>On the other hand, if you land/take-off from Seattle during the day – that’s another sight. It’s not called Emerald or Green City for nothing. Seattle is an isthmus surrounded by quite a few water bodies and mountain ranges.
It’s between the Lake Washington and Pudget Sound (which connects to the Pacific ocean about 50 miles west of Seattle) and surrounded by modern satellite cities like Redmond (Microsoft), Kirkland (Google) and Tacoma/Renton (Boeing), Bellevue (residential area).</p>

<p>And the whole area is so beautiful – you have to see it once in the summer – if you are in the USA.</p>

<p>But tonight’s experience is quite different from these sights – tonight is the first time I am flying out of Seattle at night. And I thought why do they brag that Seattle is the west coast;s 2nd largest city. Well I live and work in the heart of Seattle – and I always got the impression that it’s s small city (maybe 10 miles by 10 miles). Now when we took off – I saw that the story is indeed like the tri-state area – vast sea of lights!!! No doubt I am a prouder Seattlite (is that what we are called?) now!
That’s nowhere near the best part thought…</p>

<p>I always say and believe that man can never meet nature’s beauty.</p>

<p>So right now – I am over the Rockies. It’s 30 min pat midnight. And a few days after a full-moon (I think 2-3 days). For the record, it’s 2 days after the lunar eclipse that I saw while playing tennis!
There is a bit of cloud in the sky – more like a mist coat strewn here and there.</p>

<p>And the mountains below me are full of snow.</p>

<p>You can guess what I am about to say – Soft moonlight falling on the deep gorges and peaks on the mountains below me – strikingly highlighting the ravines and the whole terrain. And the misty clouds diffusing the moonlight in a dreamy sort of way!</p>

<p>Oh man – I really have never seen anything like this – Is this what you call ghastly beautiful?</p>

<p>There is not a single sign of humanity as far as I can see – only white snowy mountains and deep gorges – shining off the moonlight. Brings a mixture of feelings – lonely, scared and hauntingly beautiful. yes even though it’s so haunting – it’s so beautiful!</p>

<p>If you are reading this blog – please do take a flight out of Seattle at night – on a clear night – with abundant moonlight around. Well yeah – you are right – you need luck to see things – and I guess some people have all the luck! heh heh heh…</p>

<p>As for me, my colleague was talking of a hiking trip to the Bryce Canion sometime this summer – now I have to do it!</p>

<p>Good night – see you tomorrow at NY!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
